8 chapter N9 of Black Beauty this LibriVox recording is in the public
domain Black Beauty by Anna suul chapter nine merry legs Mr Bloomfield the vicar, had a large
family of boys and girls; sometimes they used to come and play with Miss Jesse and Flora.
One of the girls was as old as Miss Jesse two of the boys were older, and
there were several little ones. When they came there was plenty of work for Mery
legs for nothing pleased them so much as getting on him by turns and riding him
all about the orchard and the home paddock, and this they would do by the hour
together. One afternoon he had been out with them a long time, and when James
brought him in and put on his halter he said: “There, you rogue, mind how you behave
yourself, or we shall get into trouble.” “What have you been doing Mery legs I
asked. “Oh!” said he, tossing his little head, “I have only been giving those young
people a lesson; they did not know when they had had enough, nor when I had had
enough, so I just pitched them off backward; that was the only thing they could
understand.” “What!” said I, “you threw the children off? I thought you knew better
than that! Did you throw Miss Jesse or Miss Flora?” He looked very much offended, and
said: “Of course not; I would not do such a thing for the best oats that ever came
into the stable; why I'm as as careful of our young ladies as the master could be,
and as for the little ones it is I who teach them to ride. When they seem
frightened or a little unsteady on my back I go as smooth and as quiet as old
when she is after a bird; and when they are all right I go on again faster,
you see, just to use them to it; so don't you trouble yourself preaching to me I'm
the best friend and the best riding Master those children have.
It is not them, it is the boys; boys,” said he, shaking his man are
quite different; they must be broken in as we were broken in where we were Cults
and just be taught what's what. The other children had ridden me about for nearly
2 hours, and then the boys thought that it was their turn, and so it was, and I
was quite agreeable. They rode me by turns, and I galloped them about, up and
down the fields and all about the orchard, for a good hour. They had each
had a great hazel stick for a riding whip and laid it on a little too hard;
but I took it in good part, till at last
I thought we had had enough, so I stopped
two or three times by way of a hint. Boys,
you see, think a horse or a pony is like a steam engine or a thrashing machine
and can go on as long and as fast as they please; they never think that a pony
can get tired, or have any feelings; so as the one who was whipping me could not
understand I just rose up on my hind legs and let him slip off behind— —that was all.
He mounted me again, and I did the same.
Then the other boy got on and as soon as
he began to use his stick I laid him on
the grass, and so on, till they were able to understand— —that was all. They are not
bad boys; they don't wish to be cruel. I
like them very well; but you see I had to give them a lesson. When they brought me
to James and told him I think he was very angry to see such big sticks. He
said they were only fit for drover or gypsies, and not for young gentlemen
had I been you,” said Ginger, “I would have given those boys a good kick, and that
would have given them a lesson.” “No doubt you would,” said Mery legs but then I am
not quite such a fool (begging your pardon) as to anger our master or make
James ashamed of me. Besides, those children are under my charge when they
are riding; I tell you they are entrusted to me. Why, only the other day I heard our
master say to Mrs Bloomfield My dear madam, you need not be anxious about the
children; my old Mery legs will take as much care of them as you I could; I
assure you I would not sell that pony for any money he's so perfectly
good-tempered and trustworthy;' and do you think I am such an ungrateful brute as
to forget all the kind treatment I've had here for 5 years, and all the trust
that they place in me, and turned vicious because a couple of ignorant boys used me
badly? No, no! you never had a good place where they were kind to you, and so you
don't know, and I'm sorry for you; but I can tell you good places make good
horses. I wouldn't vex our people for anything; I love them, I do,” said Mary legs
and he gave a low “ho, ho, ho!” through his
nose, as he used to do in the morning when he heard James's footstep at the
door. “Besides,” he went on, “if I took the kicking where should I be? Why, sold off
in a jiffy, and no character, and I might find myself slaved about under a
butcher's boy, or worked to death at some seaside place where no one cared for me,
except to find out how fast I could go, or be flogged along in some cart with
three or four great men in it going out for a Sunday spree, as I have often seen
in the place I lived in before I came here; no,” said he, shaking his head, “I hope
I shall never come to
that end of chapter